Guide to the Archives Union File (AUF), Section 9: Boxes 507-571
Archives Union File (AUF), Section 9: Boxes 507-571
Kheel Center for Labor- Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Archives Union File (AUF), Section 9: Boxes 507-571
6046
Kheel Center
388.2 linear ft.
Pamphlets, publications.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
The Archives Union File is a collection of publications of United States labor unions. Included is information on the American Institute for Free Labor Development. The AUF collection consists largely of pamphlets and publications of unions, collected by the Kheel Center.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Due to the volume of material in this collection the finding aid has been divided into twelve sections.
Section 1: Boxes 1-63
Section 2: Boxes 64-126
Section 3: Boxes 127-191
Section 4: Boxes 192-256
Section 5: Boxes 257-319
Section 6: Boxes 319.1-378
Section 7: Boxes 379-442
Section 8: Boxes 443-506
Section 9: Boxes 507-571
Section 10: Boxes 572-635
Section 11: Boxes 636-699
Section 12: Boxes 700-704
Boxes 650-659 and 661-662 have not been inventoried at this time.
SUBJECTS
Names:
AFL-CIO --Archives; AFL-CIO. American Institute for Free Labor Development--Archives; AFL-CIO. Building and Construction Trades Dept.--Archives; AFL-CIO. Department of Economic Research--Archives; AFL-CIO. Education Department--Archives; AFL-CIO. Executive Council--Archives; AFL-CIO. Human Resources Development Institute--Archives; AFL-CIO. Industrial Union Department--Archives; AFL-CIO. Legislative Department--Archives; AFL-CIO. Public Employees Department--Archives; AFSCME --Archives; Air Line Pilots Association --Archives; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union --Archives; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union. Research Department--Archives; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America --Archives; American Association of University Professors --Archives; American Federation of Government Employees --Archives; American Federation of Labor --Archives; American Federation of Musicians --Archives; American Federation of Teachers --Archives; American Federation of Television and Radio Artists --Archives; American Guild of Musical Artists --Archives; American Postal Workers Union --Archives; Association of Flight Attendants (U.S.) --Archives; Bakery, Confectionary and Tobacco Workers International Union --Archives; Coalition of Labor Union Women (U.S.) --Archives; Communication Workers Union --Archives; Communications Workers of America --Archives; Congress of Industrial Organizations --Archives; Federation of Westinghouse Independent Salaried Unions --Archives; Hotel & Restaurant Employees and Bartenders International Union --Archives; Illinois State AFL-CIO --Archives; Industrial Workers of the World --Archives; International Association of Bridge, Structural and Ornamental Iron Workers --Archives; International Association of Fire Fighters --Archives; International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers --Archives; International Brotherhood of Painters and Allied Trades --Archives; International Brotherhood of Teamsters --Archives; International Ladies' Garment Workers Union --Archives; International Ladies' Garment Workers Union. Educational Department--Archives; International Longshoremens and Warehousemens Union --Archives; International Typographical Union --Archives; International Union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers --Archives; International Union of North American Laborers --Archives; International Union, Allied Industrial Workers of America --Archives; International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America --Archives; International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America --Archives; International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. Ford Dept. --Archives; International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers --Archives; Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.) --Archives; National Association of Postal Supervisors --Archives; National Maritime Union of America --Archives; National Writers Union (U.S.) --Archives; New York State AFL-CIO --Archives; New York State United Teachers --Archives; Oil, Chemical and Atomic Workers International Union --Archives; Screen Actors Guild --Archives; Service Employees International Union --Archives; Sheet Metal Workers International Union --Archives; Teamsters for a Democratic Union --Archives; Textile Workers Union of America --Archives; United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry --Archives; United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America --Archives; United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers --Archives; United Glass & Ceramic Workers of North America --Archives; United Mine Workers of America --Archives; United Office and Professionals Workers of America --Archives; United Rubber, Cork, Linoleum and Plastic Workers of America --Archives; United Steelworkers of America --Archives; Utility Workers Union of America --Archives; Writer's Guild of America --Archives
Subjects:
Agricultural laborers--Labor unions; Airlines--Employees--Labor unions; Textile workers--Labor unions; Barbers--Labor unions; Building-service employees--Labor unions; Clothing workers--Labor unions; Construction workers--Labor unions; Automobile industry workers--Labor unions; Bakery employees--Labor unions; Transport workers--Labor unions; Fire fighters--Labor unions; Electricians--Labor unions; Plumbers--Labor unions; Teachers--Labor unions; Glassworkers--Labor unions; Restaurants--Employees--Labor unions; Postal service--Employees--Labor unions; Rubber industry and trade--Labor unions
Form and Genre Terms:
Pamphlets.; Publications
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
Other sections of this collection:
6046: Archives Union File (AUF)
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 1: Boxes 1-63
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 2: Boxes 64-126
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 3: Boxes 127-191
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 4: Boxes 192-246
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 5: Boxes 257-319
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 6: Boxes 319.1-378
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 7: Boxes 379-442
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 8: Boxes 443-506
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 10: Boxes 572-635
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 11: Boxes 636-699
6046: Archives Union File (AUF), Section 12: Boxes 700-704
Boxes 650-659 and 661-662 have not been inventoried at this point.
Related Collections:
6046 mf: Archives Union File on Microfilm
CONTAINER LIST
- UAW (International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America) (Box 507, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: UAW-Chrysler child care program, 1988; Publication (Box 507, Folder 1)
    Language: English.
  - Item 2: UAW-GM Human Resource Center - looseleaf manual to highlight different subjects, 1989; Publication (Box 507, Folder 1)
- UAW (International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America), Publication (Box 507, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Ammunition, 1976; Publication (Box 507, Folder 2)
    Notes: v.17:no.10 (1976:Nov.)
    Format: Publication
  - Item 2: Women in society and 50th Anniversary of Woman's right to vote, 1970; Publication (Box 507, Folder 2)
    Notes: Flyer
  - Item 3: When I say NO, I mean NO. Sexual harassment is against the law, 1991; Publication (Box 507, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: When I say NO, I mean NO. Sexual harassment is against the law, 1991; Publication (Box 507, Folder 2)
    Notes: Flyer. Copy 2.
- UAW (International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America), Publication (Box 507, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Memorandum of agreement, 1992; Publication (Box 507, Folder 3)
    Author: Saturn Corporation
  - Item 2: Managerial and technological innovations at Saturn Corporation, 1992; Publication (Box 507, Folder 3)
    Author: Saturn Corporation; Richard G. Lefauve; Arnoldo C. Hax
    Notes: Article. Copy 2.
  - Item 3: University of Michigan 1991 Management briefing seminar, Publication (Box 507, Folder 3)
    Author: Saturn Corporation; Alan G. Perriton
  - Item 4: AIAG Presentation - "A Different kind of car - a different kind of company - a different materials management", 1992; Publication (Box 507, Folder 3)
    Notes: Copy 2.
  - Item 5: Forming the future: the marriage of people and technology at Saturn, 1990; Publication (Box 507, Folder 3)
  - Item 6: Looking Ahead, Publication (Box 507, Folder 3)
    Notes: v.13:no.4
  - Item 7: The Saturn Story, 1992; Publication (Box 507, Folder 3)
  - Item 8: Saturn's synchronous Engineering, 1993; Publication (Box 507, Folder 3)
- UAW (International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America), Publication (Box 507, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Crossroads for America: choosing a better future for American industry and the American people, 1986; Publication (Box 507, Folder 4)
  - Item 2: Building America's future: alternatives to economic decline, 1987; Publication (Box 507, Folder 4)
- UAW (International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America), Publication (Box 507, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: If you had a third hand, Publication (Box 507, Folder 5)
    Notes: Broadside
  - Item 2: Is it really more blessed to give than to receive?, Publication (Box 507, Folder 5)
  - Item 3: Why monkey around with your overtime?, Publication (Box 507, Folder 5)
  - Item 4: Security, Publication (Box 507, Folder 5)
  - Item 5: Looks silly, doesn't it?, Publication (Box 507, Folder 5)
  - Item 6: Why worry, worry is one of our biggest, Publication (Box 507, Folder 5)
  - Item 7: This is the UAW-CIO, 1948; Publication (Box 507, Folder 5)
  - Item 8: The Local Union Financial Officers: duties, procedures, guidelines, principles, 1987; Publication (Box 507, Folder 5)
  - Item 9: Boycott Colt Action Kit, 1987; Publication (Box 507, Folder 5)
  - Item 10: Guide for UAW: Local Union, Election, Committees, 1987; Publication (Box 507, Folder 5)
  - Item 11: The President's job: a guide to the responsibilities and duties of a President of a UAW Local Union, 1987; Publication (Box 507, Folder 5)
- UAW (International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America), Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Unity News - Local 259, 1986-1987 (Box 507, Folder 6)
    Notes: v.10:no.1 (1986/1987:Winter)
  - Item 2: Unity News - Local 259, 1987; Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
    Notes: v.10:no.2 (1987:Spring/Summer)
  - Item 3: Unity News - Local 259, 1988; Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
    Notes: v.88:no.1 (1988:Winter)
  - Item 4: 26th Constitutional Convention, 1980; Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
  - Item 5: 27th Constitutional Convention, 1983; Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
  - Item 6: News UAW - UAW wires strong support for striking Polish workers, 1988; Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
  - Item 7: News UAW - Jai Alai Players vote to join UAW, 1988; Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
  - Item 8: UAW trustees' Semi-Annual audit report - blank form, Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
  - Item 9: UAW Local union activists choose a new style of education, 1978; Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
  - Item 10: UAW Administrative Letter, 1981; Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
    Notes: v.33: letter no.2.
  - Item 11: News UAW - Reforms needed to end backsliding in Workers' compensation, Fraser says, 1980; Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
  - Item 12: News UAW - UAW leadership overwhelmingly endorses Carter-Mondale ticket, 1980; Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
  - Item 13: Fraser named as President of the Institute of Collective Bargaining & Group Relations, 1983; Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
    Notes: Press release.
  - Item 14: Washington Report, 1988; Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
    Notes: v.28:no.13 (1988:Apr. 18)
  - Item 15: Join us! Earth Day '90 is April 22, 1990; Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
    Notes: Advertisement.
  - Item 16: The UAW makes us strong, 1987; Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
    Notes: Workshop booklet
  - Item 17: Audio Visual Aids, Catalog, 1987; Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
  - Item 18: The Local Union Standing Committees and how they work, 1987; Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
  - Item 19: The Local Union Recording Secretary, 1987; Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
  - Item 20: Union Label Committee Guidebook, 1987; Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
  - Item 21: Learn thru discussion, 1987; Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
  - Item 22: 10 Points for meetings, 1987; Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
  - Item 23: Economic dislocation: plant closings, plant relocations, and plant conversion, 1979; Publication (Box 507, Folder 6)
- UAW (International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America), Publication (Box 507, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Unity News - Local 259, 1988; Publication (Box 507, Folder 7)
    Notes: v.88:no.2 (1988:Fall)
  - Item 2: FED Expressions - A new voice for Federal Express Employees, 1993; Publication (Box 507, Folder 7)
  - Item 3: FED Expressions -- Happy Holidays, 1993; Publication (Box 507, Folder 7)
    Notes: Special Issue.
  - Item 4: Boycott Colt Action Kit, 1987; Publication (Box 507, Folder 7)
  - Item 5: Joint Process in selected General Motors Plants, 1988; Publication (Box 507, Folder 7)
  - Item 6: Our working future: a guide to new technology, 1985; Publication (Box 507, Folder 7)
- BCT (Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union), Publication (Box 508, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Lo que su Union hace por usted, Publication (Box 508, Folder 1)
    Notes: Advertisement
    Language: Spanish.
  - Item 2: looseleaf pages - Working with members who are learning English; Steward recognition programs; Release time for Union Stewards, 1991; Publication (Box 508, Folder 1)
    Notes: 2 copies.
  - Item 3: Providing child care at union meetings: a guide for local union officers, 1992; Publication (Box 508, Folder 1)
    Notes: Article.
  - Item 4: BCT-PAC works for you, 1984; Publication (Box 508, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: What your union does for you, 1991; Publication (Box 508, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: What your union does for you, 1991; Publication (Box 508, Folder 1)
    Notes: Advertisement. Copy 2
  - Item 7: Meeting tomorrow's challenges today: reports of the: Leadership Development Task Force, Youth Involvement Task Force, Technology Task Force, 1990; Publication (Box 508, Folder 1)
  - Item 8: Meeting tomorrow's challenges today: reports of the: Leadership Development Task Force, Youth Involvement Task Force, Technology Task Force, 1990; Publication (Box 508, Folder 1)
  - Item 9: A review of the past ten years of the Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union: 1978-1988, Publication (Box 508, Folder 1)
- UAW (International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America), Publication (Box 508, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Research Bulletin, 1992; Publication (Box 508, Folder 2)
    Author: Research Department
    Notes: October 1992.
  - Item 2: The UAW Escalator Clause (COLA), 1992; Publication (Box 508, Folder 2)
    Notes: Revised Jan. 1992
  - Item 3: Fast track to decline?: North American Free Trade Agreement, 1993; Publication (Box 508, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: Our vision for America: a UAW program for economic growth and social justice, 1992; Publication (Box 508, Folder 2)
- UAW (International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America); Ford Motor Company, Publication (Box 508, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: UAW-Ford Employe involvement - Workshop folder, Publication (Box 508, Folder 3)
  - Item 2: UAW-Ford Employe involvement - EI it makes the difference, Publication (Box 508, Folder 3)
  - Item 3: UAW-Ford - National Joint Committee on Employe Involvement -- To compete: we need each other, Publication (Box 508, Folder 3)
  - Item 4: UAW-Ford - What's it all about, 1980; Publication (Box 508, Folder 3)
  - Item 5: The Work Live Review, 1982; Publication (Box 508, Folder 3)
    Notes: v.1:no.1 (1982)
  - Item 6: The Work Live Review, 1982; Publication (Box 508, Folder 3)
    Notes: v.1:no.1 (1982). Copy 2.
  - Item 7: The Sharonville Story: Worker Involvement at a Ford Motor Company Plant, Publication (Box 508, Folder 3)
    Notes: Article reprinted from "The Innovative Organization: Productivity Programs in Action"
  - Item 8: UAW-Ford Employe involvement: a special survey report, Publication (Box 508, Folder 3)
  - Item 9: EI UAW-Ford, Employe Involvement:A handbook: on the UAW-Ford process for local unions and management, 1980; Publication (Box 508, Folder 3)
  - Item 10: EI UAW-Ford, Employe Involvement:A handbook: on the UAW-Ford process for local unions and management, 1980; Publication (Box 508, Folder 3)
  - Item 11: EI UAW-Ford, Employe Involvement: Handbook II: concepts and ideas for continuing progress, 1983; Publication (Box 508, Folder 3)
  - Item 12: EI UAW-Ford, Employe Involvement: Handbook II: concepts and ideas for continuing progress, 1983; Publication (Box 508, Folder 3)
- UAW (International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America); Ford Motor Company, Publication (Box 508, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: The Sharonville Story: Worker Involvement at a Ford Motor Company Plant, Publication (Box 508, Folder 4)
    Notes: Article reprinted from "The Innovative Organization: Productivity Programs in Action". Copy 2.
  - Item 2: UAW-Ford Employe Development and Training Program, Publication (Box 508, Folder 4)
    Notes: Workshop folder and material
  - Item 3: Establishing a loca UAW-Ford Employe Development and Training Program - "Preliminary", 1982; Publication (Box 508, Folder 4)
  - Item 4: 1982 UAW-Ford documents establishing the UAW-Ford Employe Development and Training Program and its National Development and Training Center, Publication (Box 508, Folder 4)
  - Item 5: General Information Summary, 1983; Publication (Box 508, Folder 4)
  - Item 6: General Information Summary, 1984; Publication (Box 508, Folder 4)
  - Item 7: Announcing: New Avenues for Employe Growth, 1983; Publication (Box 508, Folder 4)
- UAW (International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America), Publication (Box 508, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Hazardous substances: fact sheets, Publication (Box 508, Folder 5)
    Author: Health and Safety Department
- International Brotherhood of Boilermakers, Iron Ship Builders, Blacksmiths, Forgers, and Helpers, Publication (Box 509, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Partial report: Committee on Constitution and Law - 27th Consolidated Convention, 1986; Publication (Box 509, Folder 1)
  - Item 2: Brotherhood LEAP manual, 1986; Publication (Box 509, Folder 1)
- BBF (International Brotherhood of Boilermakers, Iron Ship Builders, Blacksmiths, Forgers, and Helpers), Publication (Box 509, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Constitution, 1986; Publication (Box 509, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: Constitution, 1991; Publication (Box 509, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: Twenty-seventh consolidated convention, 1986; Publication (Box 509, Folder 2)
- BBF (International Brotherhood of Boilermakers, Iron Ship Builders, Blacksmiths, Forgers, and Helpers), Publication (Box 509, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Settlement of 1991 negotiations: Memorandum of agreement, Publication (Box 509, Folder 3)
  - Item 2: Agreement between Shell Oil Company and Local Lodge No. 483, 1988; Publication (Box 509, Folder 3)
  - Item 3: Agreement between Shell Oil Company and Local Lodge No. 483, 1984; Publication (Box 509, Folder 3)
  - Item 4: Agreement between Shell Oil Company and Local Lodge No. 483, 1990; Publication (Box 509, Folder 3)
  - Item 5: Agreement between Shell Oil Company and Local Lodge No. 483, 1990; Publication (Box 509, Folder 3)
  - Item 6: Agreement between Jacksonville Shipyards, Inc. and International Brotherhood of Boilermakers, Iron Ship Builders, Balcksmiths, Forgers & Helpers, Local 805, AFL-CIO: Effective July 9, 1985, Jacksonville, Florida, Publication (Box 509, Folder 3)
  - Item 7: Agreement Quality Service Railcar Repair Corporation, Sayre, Pennsylvania and International Brotherhood of Boilermakers, Iron Ship Builders, Balcksmiths, Forgers & Helpers, AFL-CIO, Local Lodge #196: Effective January 1, 1985 to December 31, 1987, Publication (Box 509, Folder 3)
  - Item 8: Agreement GE Railcar Repair Services Corporation, Sayre, Pennsylvania and International Brotherhood of Boilermakers, Iron Ship Builders, Balcksmiths, Forgers and Helpers, AFL-CIO, Local Lodge #196: Effective October 19, 1987 to October 18, 1990, Publication (Box 509, Folder 3)
  - Item 9: Agreement between Shell Oil Company and Local Lodge No. 483, 1986; Publication (Box 509, Folder 3)
- Binghamton Civil Service Forum, Publication (Box 509, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Agreement between the City of Binghamton and Binghamton Civil Service Forum: under Article 14 of the Public Employees Fair Employment Act, 1979-1980, Publication (Box 509, Folder 4)
- NBA (National Basketball Association), Publication (Box 509, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: National Basketball Players Association agreement, 1976; Publication (Box 509, Folder 5)
- MLB (Major League Baseball), Publication (Box 509, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Basic agreement between the American League of Professional Baseball Clubs and the National League of Professional Baseball Clubs and Major League Baseball Players Association, 1990; Publication (Box 509, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: Basic agreement between the American League of Professional Baseball Clubs and the National League of Professional Baseball Clubs and Major League Baseball Players Association, 1990; Publication (Box 509, Folder 6)
  - Item 3: Basic agreement between the American League of Professional Baseball Clubs and the National League of Professional Baseball Clubs and Major League Baseball Players Association, 1980; Publication (Box 509, Folder 6)
  - Item 4: Basic agreement between the American League of Professional Baseball Clubs and the National League of Professional Baseball Clubs and Major League Baseball Players Association, 1980; Publication (Box 509, Folder 6)
  - Item 5: Major League Baseball Players Association: Constitution and By-laws, 1976; Publication (Box 509, Folder 6)
  - Item 6: Major League Baseball Players Association: Constitution and By-laws, 1976; Publication (Box 509, Folder 6)
- MLB (Major League Baseball), Publication (Box 509, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Memorandum of settlement, Publication (Box 509, Folder 7)
  - Item 2: Memorandum of Agreement, Publication (Box 509, Folder 7)
- Boston Public Library Professional Staff Associaiton, Publication (Box 510, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Agreement between City of Boston and Boston Public Library Professional Staff Association: effective January 1, 1973: expiring: June 30, 1975, Publication (Box 510, Folder 1)
- BAC (International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen), Publication (Box 510, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Correspondence - The 1984 election campaign is in its final phase, Publication (Box 510, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: To strive for excellence: summary of the analysis and recommendations of the Project 2000 Committee of the International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen, 1985; Publication (Box 510, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: To strive for excellence: summary of the analysis and recommendations of the Project 2000 Committee of the International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen, 1985; Publication (Box 510, Folder 2)